<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hemant Kumar Singh</title>
    <link>https://iamhks.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hemant Kumar Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iamhks.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Low Level System Design Notes</title>
      <link>https://iamhks.com/posts/low-level-system-design-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamhks.com/posts/low-level-system-design-notes/</guid>
      <description>Attached below is a soft copy of my notes on Low-Level System Design. I made these with the help of Refactoring Guru website and Concept&amp;amp;Coding youtube channel.
Link to the pdf: https://github.com/iamhks/projects/blob/master/Low%20Level%20System%20Design.pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A on Life</title>
      <link>https://iamhks.com/posts/qa-on-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamhks.com/posts/qa-on-life/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! Here you’ll find answers to some of the most unpleasant/difficult questions that pop up in our minds every now and then. Since everything in the world is relative; some answers may or may not be satisfactory. Most of the answers are short and succinct to consume the least amount of time. Some answers are a little lengthy though because they need elaboration.
Isn’t it common when our friend needs some help, we’re able to give good advice; but when we’re in a similar situation we struggle through it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release your Brakes Book Summary</title>
      <link>https://iamhks.com/posts/release-your-brakes-book-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamhks.com/posts/release-your-brakes-book-summary/</guid>
      <description>This is a summary of the book Release your Brakes by James Newman. The timestamps at the top indicate the end of that chapter in the audio-book which can be found here.
Link to the pdf: https://github.com/iamhks/projects/blob/master/RYB.pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://iamhks.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamhks.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my corner of the internet! I invite you to explore my journey and passions. Here, you&amp;rsquo;ll uncover my professional experiences, skills, and interests that shape who I am today.
Profession: I am a Software Engineer II at Honeywell, where I have been working since graduating from college. In my role at Honeywell, one of the things I worked on was to independently develop and launch a full-stack SaaS offering, which served as an addition to the existing product, resulting in a new revenue source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timeline</title>
      <link>https://iamhks.com/timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamhks.com/timeline/</guid>
      <description>Unstructured Studio (First Remote Work Experience) Honeywell Aerospace, Hyderabad (First Job) National Institute of Technology Warangal (Graduate) Delhi Public School, Siliguri (Intermediate) Nepal Bharat Maitri Vidyalaya (Matriculation) </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
